# Edward E Griebel Jr.

edgriebel@gmail.com • 585-705-1093 github.com/edgriebel • linkedin.com/in/edgriebel

## **SUMMARY**

I am a full stack developer with over 20 years of consistent achievement solving diverse business problems. My wide breadth of experience in multiple industries, languages, and tools demonstrates success. I am passionate about writing code and working with people to deliver systems that solve business challenges. With 7 years remote experience I am productive in remote, hybrid, and in-office positions.

Advanced or Expert knowledge of: Python, Java, SQL, Linux, Team Leadership, Mentoring

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# Meta (Facebook)

August 2021 – Present

**Production Engineer** 

At Meta, a Production Engineer is a hybrid of Software, Site Reliability, and Systems Engineering disciplines to achieve reliability, scalability, performance, and security goals for services with billions of users.

My team, Ads Serving and Delivery, automates the dynamic allocation of Machine Learning models to compute servers for all ads displayed in Facebook and Instagram. My prior team created systems to automate creating thousands of new physical and virtual machines by simply editing files using infrastructure-as-code.

- Lead project to centralize configuration changes to ML/AI models in Meta's ad delivery stack, allowing users to safely make changes without causing negagive impacts.
- Created systems to automate firmware updates and custom BIOS settings for multiple hardware vendors across 10,000+ physical servers allowing decommissioning an obsolete internal application.
- Improved oncall and user experience by creating internal documentation, processes, and applications to detect and perform initial troubleshooting of common errors. These changes resulted in reducing oncall shift impact from over 15 to under five hours per week.
- Mentored junior and senior developers in technical and professional skill development.

Technologies: Python, Rust, SQL, Terraform

# **Rochester Institute of Technology**

2017 - Present

Adjunct Professor - Part-Time

- Currently teaching course in software engineering practices used in industry.
- Previously taught courses in Java and DBMS/SQL.

Margeta Inc. 2020 – 2021

Lead Software Engineer

- Tech lead for Credit accounting ledgers and inbound transaction APIs. Worked closely with developers, product owners, and operations to create a new service for customers to offer white-label credit cards.
- Established/enhanced processes and procedures for product development and support.
- Mentored engineers with designs and general software engineering practices.

Technologies: Java, MySQL, Spring Boot, Docker

## **Logical Operations**

Occasionally since 2020

Consultant - Part-Time

 Created teaching materials and consulted on industry best practices for new courses in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, and Data Science.

# **Catalant Technologies**

2019 - 2020

Principal Software Engineer

- Determined performance issues impacting product stability/scalability and negotiated with technical managers, product owners, Lead Architect, and CTO for resources, prioritization and resolution.
- Built consensus around and implemented processes and procedures for primary SaaS product to improve long-term supportability and developer productivity.
- Mentored junior developers in industry best practices and product platform.

Technologies: Python, Flask, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL, Docker, Elasticsearch

**Paychex** 2013 – 2019

Middleware Architect

Created system in Python to rebalance 20,000 databases among 200 Azure cloud pools with algorithmic,

- statistical, and machine learning techniques using TensorFlow, Pandas, and scikit-learn.
- Built internal inventory system with web and REST APIs providing a single source of truth for virtualized and physical hosts, JVMs, CLRs, databases, and middleware. Relationships sourced from external management systems including AppDynamics, Puppet, ServiceNow, and Oracle.
- Created custom Chaos Monkey implementation that would randomly kill middleware appliances and Java processes daily in multiple environments.
- Implemented AppDynamics on over 20,000 JVMs to replace a custom built system that collected and monitored JVM metrics, saving four FTEs annually.

Technologies: Java, JavaScript, Python, Oracle PL/SQL, Scikit-Learn, AppDynamics, Application Performance Monitoring (APM)

# **Axeda** (division of PTC)

2010 - 2013

Senior Software Engineer

Owned the integration, performance tuning, and upgrade of Cognos Business Intelligence modules. Internal technical consultant for professional services and product management teams.

# **Paychex**

Lead team of five to create three public-facing fullstack Java/JavaScript applications. Created CI/CD deployment pipeline with Hudson. Mentored new developers and delivered technical training.

## **Frontier Communications**

Created Java applications to build DSL circuits and track sales commissions. Automated generation of Excel spreadsheets from Hyperion EssBase saving \$200,000 annually (two FTEs).

# **Global Crossing** (division of Level3)

Lead multi-site teams to create Java and Perl CGI telecom applications.

# JP Morgan Chase

Created trading systems in C/C++ and tactical applications for equity derivatives and HFT trading desks.

# **BlackRock Financial Management**

Developed systems in C/C++ for MBS mortgage, Treasury, and Repo trading desks.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Georgia Institute of Technology**

M.S. in Computer Science

Expected Summer 2023

• Coursework includes Algorithms, Compilers, Computer Architecture, Software Analysis using LLVM, ML for Trading, and AI Techniques for Robotics

# **Bucknell University**

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

- Senior design project creating reference implementation of DHCP protocol for RFCs 1531 and 1534
- Concentrations in Digital Electronics and Geology

# **CERTIFICATIONS** AppDynamics Certified Implementations Professional

November 2016

# **AWARDS**

# Paychex Paragon Award for Resiliency, Paychex

January 2019

Our project, "Adaptive Load Balancing", was chosen for this annual award. It routes requests in F5 BigIP GTM and LTMs across servers and data centers based on server load, real-time statistics, and other measures to reduce outages and improve response times for services using it.

## **AppDynamics Scale Award**, AppDynamics

November 2015

Awarded by AppDynamics for successfully deploying the tool to over 2,000 JBoss, WebLogic, and Windows IIS servers across our fleet in the first year.

[Resume created in *I*H<sub>E</sub>X, check it out at github.com/edgriebel]